Ben Dwyer

Interaction Designer / Front End Developer

Woodstock Lodge
Moat Lane
Edenbridge
TN8 7DP
UK
+44 (0)1342 850411
+44 (0)7941 952721
ben@scruffian.com
scruffian.com

http://scruffian.com/ben.html

About me

I love making things.

I combine an unusual set of skills, with both a keen eye for visual detail, and a logical, methodical approach to problem solving. These complimentary abilities make me well suited to roles which use the rigors writing code to achieve an attractive aesthetic. This mix of skills enables me to understand the limitations and requirements of design and development and bridge the gap that so often exists between them.

Since April 2010 I have been building Boticca.com. As the first employee my roles have been many and varied. I took the site from its conception through to launch in October 2010. Since then we have been creating new features, and iterating on our user experience.

I have a thorough understanding of how to make the web accessible, usable and machine readable; but I strive beyond this, to create interfaces which are not just intuitive but also fun to use. I love learning; I actively seek out better ways of working. I find innovation exciting. I contribute to open source software.

When I am not making things for the internet I like to make things out of wood, food, music, words, paint and dirt.

Employment History

Boticca.com

UI/UX Designer/Developer

2010 - Present

- Responsible for all client side development.
- Responsible for defining all aspects of the user experience across the site.
- Help to define requirements for new features.
- Made the site responsive, to improve the experience for mobile users.
- Implemented behavioural driven development practices.
- Prototyping new features including an HTML5 mobile app.
- Contributed significantly to server side development for many features.
- Regular user testing, to improve the interface.
- Play a key role in the team acting as an interface between developers and the business.

ASOS.com

UI/UX Designer/Developer

2008 - 2010

- Responsible for the development of concepts through to the final production platform of ASOS.COM
- Provide technical guidance across all development teams on front end issues,
 promoting usability and accessibility and educating other developers.
- Key point of contact between the creative department and the development teams
- Develop standards for HTML, CSS and JavaScript and actively participate in all projects to ensure UI/UX design and standards are maintained
- Help develop business requirements by prototyping concepts
- Produce wireframes, static designs and user journeys from business requirements
- Understand users expectations and ensure that ASOS.com continues to stay aligned to industry movements
- Supplying innovative ideas for improvements in user experience, working practices, tools and technologies
- Achievements:
 - Provided all static designs for new community site.
 - · Complete site refresh.
 - Design/prototype/development of market leading site browsing technology.

Creation Interactive

Senior Digital Strategy Consultant

2008

- Primary interface between design and development teams, ensuring sites meet the highest standards including W3C compliance. AAA accessibility, best practice usability and well tested SEO methods
- Creating standards compliant, gracefully degrading CSS layouts
- Designing graphical representations of functional and technical specifications
- Interpreting client needs into architectural hierarchy and designing frameworks to integrate with databases
- Providing strategic input in digital marketing, focusing on business objectives to provide significant return on investment through improving digital communications using measurement, brand continuity, customer relationship management, and competitive landscape analysis.
- Writing articles on best practice in these areas (referenced by BBC)
- Account management for national government charity
- Improving designs with real-life, in-lab usability testing
- Working with users with significant disabilities in order to help develop accessibility best practice
- Clients include: Pfizer, Remploy, Acas, L'Oreal Professionnel, Employment Opportunities.

Front End Web Developer

2007 - 2008

- Creating standards compliant HTML / CSS based designs from Photoshop files
- Improving usability and accessibility
- Designing site layouts from site maps
- Linking templates to databases

Mark Hammerton Travel

E-commerce developer

2006 - 2007

- Oversaw the process of creating online holiday booking systems, integrating with existing online platforms, including ferry bookings. Process involved business needs analysis, feasibility study, best practice research, implementation timetable, design prototype, through testing, and user analysis to refine system. Required specialist skills in PHP, MySQL, AJAX and SOAP protocol.
- Improved campsite listings by making data searchable with a large number of

- variables, including map search and facility search.
- Integrated internal databases with web based applications making it simple to keep campsite information updated.
- Analysed business processes leading to creation of intranet and internal booking systems, streamlining internal systems and creating a more efficient and reliable booking process.

Trowbridge Gallery

Graphic Designer 2005-2006

- Designed and built ecommerce websites to a tight timescale, seeing the process through from business needs analysis, initial scope, implementation timetable, initial design concepts, prototype build, testing and refinement, and continuous improvement.
- Tracked visitor data to build user profiles, providing the sales team with quality, customised leads.
- Created print-ready artwork including image retouching, manipulation, acquisition etc.
- Designed brochure and magazine layouts
- Directed studio photo shoots

Side projects

I work on a number of small projects in my spare time, including web applications (open source) and some freelance web sites.

- https://scruffian.com/javascripture
- https://github.com/scruffian

Technical skills

Client side

- HTML
- CSS (LESScss, SASS, Stylus)
- Javascript (jQuery, jQuery Mobile)

Server side

- PHP (Symphony, Zend)
- mySQL
- CMS integration (WordPress, Joomla, Drupal)

Wireframing

- Axure
- Balsamiq
- Mockingbird

Mobile tools

- TitaniumAppcelerator
- Phonegap
- XCode

Graphic design

Adobe Creative
 Suite

Behavioural testing

Behat with Mink

Education

- Graduate Training Programme Hewitt Bacon & Woodrow (2003 2004)
- The University Of Reading BSc Mathematics (2000 2003)

References

Available on request.